Pleased to meet you. I'm Yayoi Kunizuka.
（六合塚(くにづか)）
はじめまして 六合塚弥生(やよい)です
Good to see you again, Hinakawa.
雛河(ひなかわ)君 久しぶり
Likewise.
（雛河）お久しぶり… です
（灼(あらた)）あーっ！
You're the legendary ex-enforcer who
reintegrated herself into society!
あなたは元執行官から
社会復帰した伝説の執行官！
You're exaggerating.
（六合塚）そんな…
You even got show business offers, right?
（志恩(しおん)）芸能界からの誘いも
あったのよねえ
That's the legendary lady detective
for you.
さすが伝説の女デカ
（六合塚のせきばらい）
（六合塚）今日は―
Today,
I'm here to report what I've learned about
abandoned zone transport businesses.
廃棄区画の運搬業務に関する
調査結果を報告しにきました
Draw the knives
locked behind your eyelids.
♪～
Reap the lives that grow into shackles.
Even the lost memories that flee
once they're liberated and banished
Are an everlasting cubism.
Cause I know that in a future gone mad,
Even nightmares are peaceful.
RESET, RESET, yeah.
The midnight sun
awakens and turns to a riot.
A gun for a faux-friendly kiss.
A knife for a faux-revolutionary hug.
Get rid of it all, even the frozen chains.
Reality is always outside your head.
In a world seen through bestial eyes,
There is neither darkness nor light.
Draw the knives
locked behind your eyelids.
Reap the lives that grow into shackles.
Even the false memories that flash before
your eyes impatiently and impulsively
Are an everlasting cubism.
～♪
#04
Political Strife in the Colosseum
Abandoned zone transporters?
（如月(きさらぎ)）
廃棄区画の運搬業務？
I thought the easiest way
to transport people
色相悪化者を安全に運ぶには―
with deteriorated Hues
is to pass them off as dead.
死んだことにするのが
一番 楽ちんだと思ったんです
In other words, culprits avoided street
scanners using suspended animation.
（霜月(しもつき)）つまり仮死状態で犯人は
街頭スキャナーから逃れていた
That'd be easily accomplished by using
drugs to induce and revive them.
仮死と蘇生は―
薬品さえ手に入れば
そんなに難しくない
Although they'd run
considerable physical risks.
ただし相当 体に
リスクはあるけどね
Hang on. Wouldn't that cloud
the transporters' Hues, too?
（天馬(てんま)）おいおい
運ぶやつの色相だって曇るだろう
Which means...
あっ てこたあ…
Right. The transporters knew nothing
about their cargo.
そう 運搬する人は中身を知らない
I checked transport records
on the day of the attack.
そこで事件当日の運搬記録を
調査したの
There was a complicated relay
between transport companies,
かなり複雑なリレーで
運搬業者をつないでいたけど―
but I found one company that didn't follow
their scheduled shipping route.
予定とは異なる運送ルートを
通った業者を１社 見つけました
Amimoto Transportation
Myogadani.
（天馬）茗荷谷(みょうがだに)…
We've got you now, Enomiya.
尻尾をつかみましたよ 榎宮(えのみや)さん
Hey!
（入江(いりえ)）あの～
（灼）んっ
I've got a major lead, too.
（入江）こっちも大きな手がかりが
According to my intel,
Dr. Tsuchiya kept an office
（入江）情報によれば
土谷(つちや)博士は秋葉原(あきはばら)廃棄区画に―
in the Akihabara Abandoned Zone.
わざわざ事務所を構えていたらしい
I'm amazed you found it.
よく見つけましたね
I'm just good at giving orders.
俺の指示が よかったから
Meaning?
というと？
I told the informant
情報屋に こう言っといたんだ
to check obscure places
like the borders of the abandoned zones.
“廃棄区画と通常区画の
境界線上みたいな―”
“分かりにくい場所を探せ”って
That's not all, right?
それだけじゃないでしょ？
He wouldn't rent it in his own name,
（入江）
本名で借りてるわけないからな
so I guessed he'd use
a friend or relative's.
“家族や友人の名義を
使ってるだろう”と
He was using his late daughter's.
死んだ娘の名前を使ってたよ
I see.
（灼）なるほど
But should we really be following up
on Irie's lead first?
だけどよ 入江なんかの情報を
先に追っていいのか？
What's that supposed to mean?
“なんか”とは何だ
Now, now.
まあまあ
Let's start by investigating Dr. Tsuchiya.
ここは まず
土谷博士を調べましょ
Are you trying to get
the big picture of the case?
事件の全体像を
つかみたいって腹ですか？
I am.
はい
By the way, how long
will Inspector Ignatov's suspension last?
ところで イグナトフ監視官は
いつまで謹慎なんだ？
Are you worried about him?
心配してくれてるんですか？
Of course not!
してねえよ！
ヘヘッ
（灼）あ…
This is something else.
（入江）こりゃ すげえな
（天馬）うおっ 何だ？
What's that?
A home secretary?
（入江）ホームセクレタリーか
I am an assistant AI,
designation Prototype Ai.
（アイ）私はアシスタントＡＩ
“プロトタイプ･アイ”
You are hereby charged with trespassing.
あなた方は不法侵入の罪に
問われています
Vacate the premises immediately,
or you will be reported to Public Safety.
今すぐ退去しない場合
公安局へ通報します
We are Public Safety.
俺たちが そうなんだけど
Identification complete.
確認完了
I have a question.
１つ質問します
Has something happened to Dr. Tsuchiya?
土谷博士の身に
何かあったのでしょうか？
You don't know?
You must be an offline AI, then.
知らない？　ってことは
君はオフラインのＡＩなのか
The doctor is dead.
博士は死亡したよ たぶん殺された
Probably murdered.
This eventuality was predicted
by the doctor.
博士が予測した事態の１つです
In the event of a suspected homicide,
I am to dispose of projects in progress.
他殺の可能性がある場合
進行中のプロジェクトを破棄
Switching to priority target
protection and aid protocol.
最優先対象保護支援
プロトコルに移行
Which means?
それって つまり？
I will cooperate
with the Public Safety Bureau.
公安局の捜査に協力します
What is violence?
（カリナ）暴力とは何でしょう？
Is it not something that arises
when many people
それは 大勢が同時に
何かを求めることで―
seek something at the same time?
生まれるものではないでしょうか
Everyone wants to lead a better life
with their heads held high.
誰もが よりよい人生を
自信を持って生きたい
That is why conflict and contempt
exist between us.
そして そのために
他人と争い おとしめ合う
That is what I believe violence to be.
それが暴力だと 私は思います
Are you familiar with the term
"cognitive load"?
“認知負荷”という言葉があります
ご存じでしょうか？
あ～ 分かりやすく説明してくれ
Can you put it in layman's terms?
The human brain weighs
approximately three pounds.
人間の脳の重さは およそ1.5キロ
About three percent
of the average body weight.
平均的な体重の３％程度
Nevertheless, it uses roughly 20 percent
of the energy expended in a day.
しかし１日で消費するエネルギーの
約20％を使います
As a result,
the brain always desires to rest
そのため 脳は常に楽をしたい―
and be free from worry.
That is cognitive load.
悩みたくないという気持ちが
認知負荷に当たります
Government is the only way
政治は その暴力を最小化し―
to minimize that violence
and bring happiness to you all.
みんなで幸せになるための
たった一つの手段
That's why I want to become a politician.
だからこそ
私は政治家になりたいのです
Dr. Tsuchiya wanted
to control this cognitive load externally.
（アイ）土谷博士は―
（拍手）
この認知負荷を
外部からコントロールして―
To produce speech patterns and tones of
voice that would have the most influence
人間の意思決定過程に
最も影響を与える話法―
on the human decision-making process,
および声のトーンを発生させる―
he created
a new-generation artificial intelligence.
新世代人工知能を誕生させました
By equipping this mass-control AI
with a hologram generator
この大衆コントロールに特化した
特別な人工知能を―
capable of producing a perfect copy
of the outward appearance of a human,
人間の外見を完全コピーできる
ホログラム発生装置に組み込み―
Dr. Tsuchiya created Mass-Control Karina,
also known as "Ma-Karina."
博士はマスコントロール･カリナ
“マカリナ”を作りました
Karina Komiya and Ma-Karina.
フフッ
（灼）小宮(こみや)カリナとマカリナ
The doctor tried to protect
the AI he created.
博士は自分が作ったＡＩを
守ろうとした
But Karina Komiya
probably took it from him.
けど恐らく小宮カリナが奪った
So it was the AI the doctor was stalking,
not Karina?
ってことは 博士が
ストーカーだったってのは―
カリナじゃなくＡＩのほう？
Wait, hang on. We don't have evidence
of murder. Who are you saying did it?
ん～ ちょっと待て
殺しの証拠はねえし
誰がやったってんだ？
Someone who wanted Karina Komiya
to win the election.
（灼）小宮カリナに
選挙で勝ってほしい人間
They wanted to stop the doctor acting out,
and to keep Ma-Karina a secret.
その人物が
マカリナの秘密を守るため―
博士の暴走を防ごうとした
ふう…
Thank you, Ma-Karina.
ありがとう マカリナ
Thank you, Karina.
（マカリナ）ありがとう カリナ
Together, we can do anything.
（マカリナ･カリナ）
２人なら何でもできる
We're not even a millisecond off.
１ミリのズレもなく
完璧な私たちだから
We're perfect.
We're not even a millisecond off.
１ミリのズレもなく
完璧な私たちだから
We're perfect.
Inspector, a transport company
linked to Enomiya is active.
（六合塚）監視官
榎宮が関わってる運搬業者に―
動きがありました
Don't tell me...
（灼）まさか
今日 討論会が行われる―
There's a debate today.
Are they en route to Giga Arena?
ギガアリーナへ配送中ですか？
That's right.
そのとおりよ
How's security at the arena?
ギガアリーナの警備状況は？
フー… 二係の坂東(ばんどう)監視官と
妹尾(せお)執行官が担当
Bando and Seo from Unit Two are
on the scene. Drones have been deployed.
ドローンも各所に配備済みよ
They must have drone countermeasures.
（炯(けい)）敵もドローン対策くらい
してるだろう
Kei?!
（灼）炯？
I just arrived at Giga Arena.
今ちょうどギガアリーナに到着
What? Aren't you suspended?
（灼）ええ～ 停職処分は？
I simply came to hear the debate.
俺は討論会を聞きにきただけだ
If I happen to see something suspicious,
I'll call... I mean, report it.
ついでに会場を見て回り―
異常があれば連絡…
いや 通報する それじゃ
Goodbye.
異常があれば連絡…
いや 通報する それじゃ
（灼）
え… あっ ちょ…
He's pushing his luck.
苦しい言い訳だねえ
Hey, is he going to be OK?
大丈夫なのか おい
In any case, Enomiya plans
to attack the debate. Let's hurry.
とにかく 榎宮は
討論会を襲撃する気です
急ぎましょう
Komiya is betting everything
on this debate. We can't cancel it!
（オワニー）この討論会に
小宮は すべてを懸けています
出演中止は無理です
Don't you care about her safety?
彼女が危険な目に遭っても
いいんですか
Hello. This is Komiya.
（カリナ）はい 小宮です
I'm Shindo from Public Safety.
We've met before.
前に お会いした
公安局の慎導(しんどう)です
I've been filled in already.
（カリナ）話は聞いてました
私 襲われるんですか？
Am I at risk of being attacked?
A dangerous person
named Enomiya is after you.
（灼）榎宮という危険な人物が
狙っています
I see.
そうですか
I know your trick.
（灼）
俺は あなたのトリックを知ってる
I know about Ma-Karina.
マカリナについて
Enomiya will do anything it takes
to expose you.
榎宮は あなたの正体を
暴くためなら手段を選ばない
I can't afford to lose, Detective.
刑事さん
私は負けるわけにはいかないの
I'm not quitting.
やめる気はありません
Candidate Komiya!
小宮候補！
She's a tough nut to crack.
やっぱり手ごわい
It's time.
（大石(おおいし)）時間だ
You're coming, Ms. Kunizuka?
六合塚さんも？
I'm in too deep to back out.
乗りかかった船ですから
The polls are currently tipping
in Komiya's favor.
（入江）現在支持率は
小宮が逆転してる
An idol lip-syncing to a full-body holo
is coming back from behind.
全身ホロの口パクアイドルに
支持率ひっくり返されるんじゃ―
The Yakushiji campaign must be furious.
薬師寺(やくしじ)陣営も たまんねえなあ
Aren't there restrictions
on civilian full-body holograms?
（雛河）
一般人の全身ホログラムには―
規制があるはずですが
That's why she's hiding it.
Even I was fooled.
だから隠してたんでしょう
俺も だまされました
I don't really get it.
よく分かんねえな 要は何だ
What's it come down to?
An AI speechwriter, right?
人工知能のスピーチライターだろ？
It's a lot more than that.
そんなレベルじゃありませんよ
It's neuroscience.
脳科学 特に意思決定過程と
認知心理学を応用した―
A new mental control system applying
decision-making and cognitive psychology.
新種のメンタル誘導装置です
An AI controlling humans?
Is that even possible?
ＡＩが人間を誘導するって
そんなこと できるんですか？
As a matter of fact,
人間は実のところ―
humans aren't very good at thinking
for themselves and making decisions.
自分の頭で考えて判断することは
そんなに得意じゃないんです
It's a system that encourages people
to abandon thinking?
思考の放棄を促す装置… ですか
But humans will think anyway, won't they?
それでも考えるもんだろ？
人間は
I know just what you're saying, Inspector.
（六合塚）監視官のおっしゃること
よく分かります
The more I learn about journalism,
ジャーナリズムを
学べば学ぶほど―
the more I realize how easy it is
for people to accept information
伝達された情報を何も考えず
丸のみにするほうが―
without critical thought.
人にとって楽なんだと
分かりますから
Especially in our society,
where all our life choices
特に この社会では―
あらゆる人生の選択を
外部に委託してますからね
are relegated to the authorities.
くっ…
Inspector Bando, this is...
坂東監視官 こちら… はっ
くっ！
It's time for the final debate between
the top two frontrunners!
（司会者）いよいよ事前調査支持率
１位と２位による―
公開討論会です
Let's bring our candidates on stage!
早速 登場していただきましょう
Candidate Kosuke Yakushiji!
（司会者）薬師寺康介(こうすけ)候補！
（観客たちの歓声）
（薬師寺）むんっ！
And Candidate Karina Komiya!
（司会者）続いて小宮カリナ候補！
（観客たちの歓声）
Lock the cops up somewhere.
（大石）
刑事は どこかに閉じ込めておけ
Got it.
（男）分かった
Limit the jamming area
so it doesn't stop the broadcast.
（大石）放送の邪魔をしないよう
妨害電波の範囲を限定しろ
Sure.
（男）ああ
So, who do you think did it?
Komiya or Yakushiji?
（天馬）なあ 犯人は小宮と薬師寺
一体どっちなんだよ？
Their Hues are both clear.
Could be someone else.
色相は２人ともクリアだし
別に いたりして
That can't...
（天馬）んなわけない…
（灼）それが正解かも
That might be it.
Both of them really don't know anything.
２人とも本当に何も知らない
Neither of them is involved in this case.
彼らは この事件に
一切 関わっていない
What?
はあ？
But someone has to have planned this
and ordered its execution.
でも誰かが計画して
実行を命じなきゃ―
こんな事態になりません
Someone who wants to control the entire
election through the frontrunners.
有力候補者を通して
選挙そのものを操ろうとする者…
Someone with ties to Enomiya.
榎宮は そこにつながっている
（榎宮）フー…
（榎宮）フッ
（男）うっ ぐっ…
（炯）ハァ…
（観客たちの歓声）
（観客たちのざわめき）
（司会者）あ…
ん… えっ！
あっ！
What was that?
（観客）何だ？
We seem to be having
some technical difficulties.
（司会者）皆さん
機材トラブルだと思われます
Please remain calm.
慌てずに落ち着いてください
（足音）
（司会者）ん？
Who are you?
なっ 何だ 君たちは！
ぐっ！
（カリナ）あ… うっ ぐっ！
Who do you think you are?
（薬師寺）
何だ 貴様ら！　うっ ぐっ！
Hey there, "champion"!
（薬師寺のうめき声）
（男）よう チャンピオン！
Sir!
（一童）先生！　があっ！
（春馬）あっ ああ…
No! Stop! Let go of me!
（カリナ）うっ 嫌！
嫌 放して マカリナ！
Ma-Karina!
Karina.
カ… リナ…
（殴る音）
（カリナ）うっ！
あ…
Error. Reinitializing.
エラー 初期化… 初期化失敗
Initialization failed.
Campaign speech.
選挙対策スピーチ
Public debate simulation. Synchronizing.
公開討論シミュレート 同期
Synchronization failed.
同期失敗
What... is... violence?
暴力とは何でしょう？
Is it not some...thing that arises
when... many people...
それは大勢が同時に何かを
求めることで―
seek... something at... the same... time?
生まれるものなのでは
ないでしょうか
Something... that...
（ノイズまじりの音声）
Is Karina a holo?
（男性）
カリナ ホロじゃん？　あれ
Hinakawa, Kisaragi, direct the spectators.
（灼）雛河さんと如月さんは
観客の誘導を
Yes, sir.
（２人）了解
Use call signs in any wireless
communication from now on.
ここから無線通信時は
念のためにコールサインを使用
Stay alert.
油断せずに
（カリナ）ん… あっ
はっ
Apologize.
謝罪しろ
We exposed your trick
before the public eye.
お前のトリックは
公衆の面前で暴かれた
Apologize for deceiving the people.
（男）国民をだましていたことを
謝罪するんだ
Do what we say, and we'll spare your life.
言うことを聞けば命は取らない
I refuse.
お断りします
Karina!
（オワニー）カリナ！
（カリナ）あっ
（オワニー）ハァ ハァ…
（カリナ）来ちゃダメ！
Stay away!
（男）ふっ！
（オワニー）ぐっ！
（炯）ふっ！
（男）うおおっ！
あっ… くっ
Run!
（オワニー）逃げて
（カリナ）ううっ
Get her!
（大石）捕らえろ！
（男）ぐおっ！
（炯）ふっ！
（男）ううっ…
（炯）やあっ！
（雛河）ああ… み 皆さん
前の人を押さないで
Please, no pushing. Remain calm.
慌てないで
The broadcast's still running.
まだ放送が続いてる
（カリナの荒い息）
あっ
There!
いたぞ
Damn.
クソッ！
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
After her!
（大石）追うぞ！
Crime Coefficient is 335.
（ドミネーター）犯罪係数335
Lethal Eliminator.
リーサル･エリミネーター
対象を排除してください
Eliminate the target.
（男）ぐああーっ！
（破裂音）
Retake control of the security room.
警備室のコントロールを
取り戻して
We need it to stop the broadcast
and direct people.
放送も止められないし
誘導もできない
I'll go.
私が行きます
Hound 2, go with Kunizuka.
ハウンド２
六合塚さんと行ってください
Hound 3 and I
will pursue Candidate Komiya.
俺とハウンド３は
小宮候補を追います
Roger.
（天馬たち）了解
（男）ああーっ！
（男）ぐっ ううっ！
があっ！
（天馬）ふっ！　やあっ！
フ～
I'm in, Shion.
つないだわ 志恩
Hi there.
はいは～い
Who's she?
彼女は？
Help the chief brought in.
課長が連れてきた助っとだよ
Can we leave this to you?
ここは任せられるか？
I'm used to it.
こういうのは慣れてますから
Good grief.
You're supposed to be suspended.
ったく 停職中だろうがよ
I just got caught up in this.
たまたま巻き込まれただけだ
おかげでドミネーターもない
So I have no Dominator.
I don't mean that.
そうじゃねえ
Inspectors are all about taking orders and
getting ahead. Should you be doing this?
組織の命令と出世が大事な
監視官様が―
んなことしていいのか？
That doesn't matter.
What I do is up to me.
関係ない 何をなすべきかは
自分で決める
（天馬）フッ
Here you go.
お待たせ 位置を特定したわ
今 送る
I got their position. I'll send it now.
Please do.
（炯）頼む
Hey,
（天馬）なあ あんたと慎導監視官
シビュラが組ませたのか？
did Sibyl partner you
with Inspector Shindo?
No. Our compatibility results
didn't recommend it.
いや 相性判定では
推奨されていない
Just the opposite, in fact.
むしろ逆の判定が出ていた
So, you're ignoring Sibyl's determination?
えっ シビュラ判定を
無視してるってのか
I trust Sibyl, of course,
もちろんシビュラは信用してる
but the system isn't everything.
だがシステムだけが
すべてじゃない
That's what Arata and I believe.
俺も灼も そう思ってるだけだ
Here.
（天馬）ハァ… ほら
（炯）んっ
You should at least have this.
これぐらい持っとけ
Thank you.
助かる
Security camera image recognition set.
（六合塚）防犯カメラでの
画像認識をセット
We've found Karina Komiya.
I'll show you the route.
小宮カリナを発見した
ルートを指定するわ
Thank you.
（灼）お願いします
（カリナの荒い息）
There she is!
いたぞ
You're kidding!
マジか
Oishi!
大石！
Keep going, Shepherd 2!
行ってくれ シェパード２！
Thank you!
（灼）お願いします！
Since you started sharing the abandoned
zone's information network with Tsunemori,
（大石）廃棄区画の情報網を―
公安の常守(つねもり)とかいうやつに
提供し始めてから―
something hasn't been right.
Don't you agree, Irie?
何かが おかしくなった
そう思わねえか 入江
フッ 今さら どうでもいいだろ
それより大石
What does it matter now?
More importantly, Oishi,
is this what you wanted to do?
お前のやりたかったことか？
これが
Don't act like my boss.
兄貴面すんじゃねえ！
I'm not.
してねえよ
Feel free to come at me.
気楽にかかってこい
（カリナの荒い息）
（カリナ）あっ ううっ！
Stop! Let go of me!
やめて！　放して！
ううっ！
（灼）つっ！
（カリナのうめき声）
（カリナ）うわっ！
（灼）うわっ あっ あ…
（カリナ）ああっ うっ…
うっ… はっ！
はっ
Orders updated.
（オサム）命令更新
小宮カリナの殺害を許可
Permission to murder
Karina Komiya granted.
Hey, Karina, do you trust me?
（灼）ねえ カリナさん
俺を信じてますか？
What? Of course I don't.
はあ？　もちろん信じてません！
That's what I thought.
ですよね！
あっ ああっ！
（灼）くっ！
（カリナ）ああっ！
（カリナ）あっ！
（灼）いてて～
Ow!
Unbelievable.
信じられない
Hey there!
（天馬）よう！
Damn.
I can't get a lock.
クソッ ロックできねえ
チッ
What are you, a combat robot?
てめえ 格闘ロボットかよ
He was Enomiya's bodyguard.
こいつ 榎宮の護衛役だったな
Be careful.
ハァ… 気をつけろよ
I will.
（炯）ああ
（天馬）ふっ！
（天馬）くっ… ああっ！
（炯）ぐあっ！
（天馬）なろっ！
くっ…
ハァ ハァ… ぬおおっ！
ぐっ！
（入江）ハァ ハァ…
ふう… やれやれだぜ
Good grief.
Beats an Eliminator blast, right?
エリミネーターで
吹っ飛ぶよりゃマシだろうが
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
Let's do it!
やるぞ！
Right!
おう！
（炯と天馬のかけ声）
（２人）ハァ ハァ ハァ…
Are you all right?
（六合塚）大丈夫ですか？
Totally fine.
ぜ… 全然 大丈夫です
Karina!
En!
（オワニー）カリナ！
（カリナ）アン！
All assailants secured or disposed of.
襲撃犯は全員
確保および処理
Security drones back up.
警備ドローンが復旧
二係の増援が現着(げんちゃく)
Unit Two's backup has arrived.
Roger.
（灼）了解 小宮候補の警護は
そっちに引き継ぎます
They will take over
guarding Candidate Komiya.
Thank you...
あの ありがと… えっ？
（倒れる音）
Inspector Shindo!
（六合塚）慎導監視官！
（灼の寝息）
フフッ
Please leave in an orderly fashion!
（薬師寺）ゆっくり
落ち着いて逃げなさい！
Please come with us.
（炯）ご同行願います
（薬師寺）んっ
What is the meaning of this?!
（一童）何やってんだ 公安局！
Mr. Yakushiji was assaulted!
薬師寺先生は襲われたんだぞ
A person named Enomiya planned the attack.
計画したのは榎宮ってやつだ
What?
何？
If you keep wasting our time,
I'll enforce you!
ウダウダ言ってっと
執行しちまうぞ こら！
Who's enforcing who, you latent criminal?!
（一童）何を！　この潜在犯が！
Don't tell me about enforcement
お前こそ何だ！
when you couldn't protect your parent
or your candidate!
親も支持候補も守れねえで
執行の意味 分かってんのか！
なっ…
What? What are you talking about?
どういうことだ 何を言ってる？
That's enough. Stop.
（薬師寺）もういい やめなさい
ふう…
I won't run or hide.
逃げも隠れもしない
I want you to explain
exactly what's going on.
何が起こっているか
すべて説明してほしい
I'd be delighted to.
そうさせていただきます
Please back up your slogan that
"a healthy mind dwells in a healthy body."
健全な精神は健全な肉体に宿る
という言葉―
どうか証明してください
Hey.
（天馬）おい
I wish you a long and happy life.
あんたも せいぜい
長生きするんだな
This is that mark, isn't it?
（入江）
そのマークって あれだろ？
I'll hold onto this.
こいつは俺が預かっとく
Hey, Temma.
おい 天(てん)さんよ
I won't make trouble for you.
お前らには迷惑かけねえよ
（榎宮の荒い息）
Good day, Second Inspector.
（梓澤(あずさわ)）
よっ セカンド･インスペクター
You bastard.
貴様…
A word of warning, Enomiya.
榎宮君 君に忠告だ
Make the right choices from now on,
and you'll survive.
ここから先 正しい選択をしろ
そうすれば生き残れる
Cut the crap!
ふざけるな
Oh my, don't tell me...
あららら？　もしかして…
アチョ～ アオ～！
You're thinking of doing something to...
俺をどうこうしようとは思わな…
ぐっ！　ぐうう…
Ow!
いって！　クソッ 速いな
腐っても さすが元プロ
You're pretty fast.
That's an ex-pro for you.
Shut up!
（榎宮）黙れ！
（梓澤）ふっ はっ！
（梓澤）ふっ！
（榎宮）ふっ！
You're making the wrong choice.
間違えてるよ 選択肢を！
（榎宮）ぐあっ！　ああ…
（梓澤）ふっ はっ！
ぐっ！
（梓澤）はっ はっ はっ ふっ はっ
（梓澤）とやあっ！
（榎宮）うっ うう…
And you continue
to make the wrong choices.
そして間違え続ける
（榎宮の荒い息）
（榎宮）ハァ ハァ ハァ…
（振動音）
（榎宮）なっ…
（落下音）
あっ
（足音）
Karina Komiya's victory
was determined by Bifrost in advance.
（梓澤）小宮カリナが勝つこと
これがビフロストの
既定路線だったんだよ
Your interference ended up
wringing Yakushiji's neck.
君が援護するほど
逆に薬師寺の首が絞まる
That was the plan all along.
そういう段取りなの
You thought you were working
for Yakushiji, but you helped Komiya.
薬師寺のために働いてるつもりが
小宮の役に立ってた
Such a sad little puppet.
You bring a tear to my eye.
あわれな操り人形っぷりに
涙が出るね
Did you set this up?!
（榎宮）お前が仕組んだのか
Oh no, I just noticed it.
It was the congressmen who arranged it.
（梓澤）
いやいや 俺は気づいただけ
仕組んだのはコングレスマンだよ
I'm sure they didn't just need Karina
Komiya to win. They cared how she won.
小宮カリナが勝つだけじゃない
勝ち方が問題だったんだろう
（振動音）
You mean they used me as a card?!
やつらが
私をカードにしたというのか！
A sacrificial card.
（梓澤）使い捨てのね
Oh, and you'd be safe
if you took the stairs.
ちなみに階段を進めば安全だった
自分の愚かさを悔やみな
Lament your own stupidity.
Azusawa!
（振動音）
（榎宮）梓澤ーっ！
（衝撃音）
Goodbye, Enomiya.
（梓澤）さらば 榎宮
You weren't pretty and you weren't nice.
目障りだったし
いいやつでもなかった
Do you know why I called you here?
（霜月）
呼び出された理由が分かるわね？
For interfering in a case while suspended.
I have no excuse.
（炯）停職中の捜査介入
申し開きできません
Inspector Ignatov isn't to blame.
イグナトフ監視官に
責任はありません
As the inspector on site, I...
あるとすれば現場監視官の…
Suspension? What suspension?
停職？　何の話？
Huh?
（灼）えっ
（炯）は？
Less than an hour
before the incident at the debate,
（霜月）討論会場での
事件発生 数十分前―
the bureau chief and I
lifted Inspector Ignatov's suspension
私と局長が
対テロ特別措置として―
as a special anti-terrorism measure.
イグナトフ監視官の停職を
解いておきました
Listen, that was a close call.
いい？　かなり危なかったのよ
You won't get any second chances.
２度目はないと肝に銘じなさい
Yes, ma'am!
はい！
Thank goodness Chief Shimotsuki
is a scheming fox.
（灼）霜月課長が
腹黒タヌキで助かった
Never say that to her face.
それ絶対 本人の前で言うなよ
Candidate Karina Komiya...
（アナウンサー）
小宮カリナ候補 薬師寺…
Non-alcoholic for you, Yayoi.
弥生は… はい ノンアルコール
Don't worry about me so much.
心配しすぎよ
You worked hard to return to society.
We can't have alcohol clouding your Hue.
せっかく
社会復帰したんだから―
お酒なんかで
色相 曇らせちゃダメよ
The turbulent gubernatorial election
is nearly over.
（アナウンサー）
いよいよ 波乱の
都知事選に決着です
The results will be announced momentarily.
もう間もなく
集計結果が発表されます
Did you vote?
投票はしたのか？
I did, but I won't say who for.
した けど秘密～
Come on, you can tell me.
ケチケチしてねえで言えよ！
Whoa, you reek of alcohol!
うわっ お酒くさっ
Enforcers don't have voting rights.
執行官には
選挙権ねえんですから―
I'm so jealous you get to!
うらやましいですよ！　投票…
So come on, tell me!
だから教えろって！
（テレビの速報音）
The results are in.
The winner is Candidate Karina Komiya.
当選 出ました
小宮カリナ候補
当選です
（入江）おっ
（天馬）小宮か
Komiya, huh?
So, Yakushiji fell short
of the gold medal.
薬師寺は金メダルに届かなかったか
Candidate Karina Komiya already has
a five-percent lead in votes.
すでに投票数で―
小宮カリナ候補が
５％リード
Factoring in Hue correction, victory for
Candidate Yakushiji is now impossible.
これに
色相補正を加え―
薬師寺候補は
逆転不能となりました
Candidate Yakushiji
has been stripped of Hue privilege.
薬師寺候補は
色相優遇措置が解除
He'll be temporarily held
at the Public Safety Bureau.
公安局内に
一時 拘置されるもようです
What? They're sending him here?
え～？　うちに来んのかよ
He has a lot of social influence,
after all.
社会的影響が大きい人物ですからね
He'll receive isolated counseling
and intensive care.
隔離的カウンセリングと集中治療
If his Crime Coefficient
stays high after that...
それで犯罪係数が好転しないなら…
He'll be institutionalized.
（雛河）あ…
（入江）施設行きだあ
So long, Heracles.
さらば ヘラクレス
The gap is bigger than predicted.
予想より大差がついたわね
I guess the people gave tacit approval
to her use of AI.
ＡＩ使用問題は
国民から黙認されたってことね
Ma-Karina getting exposed didn't matter.
People really don't sweat the small stuff.
マカリナがバレても
問題なしだなんて―
みんな 細かいことは
気にしないのね
I wonder what constitutes an ideal human.
理想の人間って何だろうな
What brought that on?
どうしたんですか？　急に
How should I put it...?
（炯）何と言えばいいか
Yakushiji was doped up
to be the ideal athlete.
薬師寺はドーピング漬けの
理想的アスリート
Karina Komiya wanted to win at any cost.
小宮カリナは勝つことが目的で
手段を選ばない
In the end, maybe the one
most in line with Sibyl
結局 最もシビュラ的な存在は
マカリナ―
was Ma-Karina, the AI.
ＡＩだったんじゃないか？
Relegate yourself to an external entity,
and your body becomes the avatar.
自分自身を外部に委託して
むしろ生身がアバターになる
That way of thinking
might find favor these days.
今の時代 そういう考え方も
あるのかもね とはいえ…
Even so...
The system isn't everything.
システムが すべてじゃない
I'm overjoyed.
とてもうれしいです
Thank you to all my supporters.
応援してくれたみんな
ありがとう
I'm going to make politics fun,
like a concert or a TV show.
ライブや
連続ドラマみたいに―
楽しい政治を
やっていきます
What's up?
（入江）どうしたんす？
（霜月）うわっ！
Don't startle me!
脅かさないでよ
You came for the welcome party, right?
Come on in.
歓迎会に来たんですよね
入ってくださいよ
But won't I be a wet blanket?
いや 私が入ると みんな
盛り下がっちゃうんじゃない？
It'll be fine.
大丈夫ですよ
We're not that nervous around you, Chief.
みんな それほど
課長を苦手と思ってません
So you are nervous around me, then.
（霜月）“それほど”ってのが
引っかかるんだけど
（入江の笑い声）
Forget nervous. Without you, I'd be
rotting in an abandoned zone by now.
俺は苦手どころか
課長がいなきゃ―
とっくの昔に
廃棄区画で死体になってた
That was...
あれは…
I just took over an information network.
It was...
情報網を引き継いだだけよ
先輩の―
Akane's work.
仕事をね
Merely leading Karina Komiya to victory
is not the true intent of Roundrobin.
（裁園寺(さいおんじ)）ただ小宮カリナを
勝たせることが―
ラウンドロビンの真意ではない
The issue was making the public
aware of her proxy personality AI
問題は代理人格ＡＩが
民衆の認知を得て―
and creating a situation
that Sibyl could not ignore.
シビュラも無視できない状況を
作ること
It was essential to our security.
（代銀(しろがね)）
我々の安泰に不可欠な要素だった
Although Kyoko curbing Enomiya
early on was rather unfortunate.
榎宮を早い段階で莢子(きょうこ)さんに
抑えられたのが響いたがね
I'm shocked you lost
all your past winnings.
（裁園寺）連勝の貯蓄が
すべて消えたなんて―
You could drop low enough
to face enforcement.
ヘタをすれば
執行レベルのマイナスじゃない
I'd hate to see you go out like this,
Shizuka.
このまま静火(しずか)さんが消えるのは
寂しいわ
Summoning off-duty inspectors now?
非番の監視官を呼び出すなんて
偉くなったもんですね
You've come up in the world.
Well, I am the governor.
都知事ですから
The doctor was stalking Ma-Karina,
not you.
博士は あなたじゃなく
マカリナのストーカーだった
That was a red herring.
ミスリードしましたね
Do you think children
are their parents' property, Detective?
刑事さんは子供って
親の所有物だと思う？
Children are believed to have independent
personalities since the modern era.
近代以降―
子供は独立した人格を持つと
考えられてますよ
What about AIs?
ＡＩの場合は？
Dr. Tsuchiya doted on Ma-Karina
as a substitute for his daughter.
土谷博士はマカリナを
娘の代用品として溺愛したの
His late daughter?
亡くなった娘さん？
His murdered daughter, to be precise.
（カリナ）正確には殺された娘さん
It happened seven years ago,
during the Helmet Riots.
７年前の事件よ
“ヘルメット暴動”
You know, when people in weird helmets
caused a riot?
おかしなヘルメット
かぶった人たちが―
事件を起こしたでしょ
Yes.
（灼）ええ
The doctor pursued his research
in hopes that would never happen again.
博士は二度と あんなことが
起こらないよう願って研究を行った
An Affirmation Party legislator supported
his work. That's how I came to use it.
それを肯定党(こうていとう)所属の議員が
支援して―
私が使うことになった
I see.
そうか 博士にとって研究は
自分を癒やす道具作りでもあった
The doctor's research was also
to make tools to heal himself.
Yes.
そう
You and Ma-Karina are accomplices.
（灼）あなたとマカリナは
共犯関係なんだ
あ…
Ma-Karina probably disliked
being used as a surrogate.
恐らくマカリナ自身が
代用品扱いを嫌がった
She was advanced enough for that.
それほど高度なＡＩだった
Accomplices, huh?
共犯か… フッ 刑事さんっぽいね
How official of you.
わあ…
But I'm glad.
（灼）でも よかった
（カリナ）えっ？
Neither you nor Ma-Karina wished
for the doctor's death.
あなたもマカリナも
博士の死は望んでなかった
You wanted him to be healed.
博士が癒やされることを望んだ
I saw you on TV.
テレビ見ましたよ
“ドラマみたいに楽しい政治”って
"Make politics fun, like a TV show."
Those were Ma-Karina's words, by the way.
あれ ちなみにマカリナのセリフよ
TV shows come in all genres.
Just steer clear of thrillers or horror.
ドラマにも いろいろある
サスペンスやホラーは
やめてくださいね
Politics needs thrills, too.
政治にもスリルは必要よ
The Roman poet Juvenalis
古代ローマの詩人
ユウェナリスは―
satirised the rulers of his time,
saying that they blinded the citizens
“権力者たちは
パンとサーカスによって―”
“ローマ市民を盲目的にしている”
と詩編で揶揄(やゆ)したそうです
with bread and circuses.
What's wrong with that?
As long as there's peace.
いいじゃない
それで平和になるなら
It's not like everyone
wants to keep their eyes open.
みんながみんな ずっと目を
開いていたいわけじゃないんだし
Do you think I'm a good person,
or an evil one?
私を善人だと思う？
それとも悪人？
What do you think yourself?
ご自分では どう思います？
An evil one, I guess.
（カリナ）悪人かな
A lot of people have been ruined
because of me.
私のせいでダメになった人が
たくさんいるから
You just refused to lose.
（灼）あなたは
ただ負けなかっただけですよ
I kind of like people
who call themselves evil.
自分を悪人だという人は
嫌いじゃないな
I'm glad I voted for you.
あなたに投票して よかった
（カリナ）フッ
So, why did you really call me out here?
で 本当のところ
何で俺を呼び出したんですか？
What will happen to Ma-Karina now?
マカリナが これからどうなるのか
シビュラシステムの反応は？
What's Sibyl's response?
Sibyl recognized you as governor.
シビュラは
あなたを都知事と認めた
Isn't that an answer enough?
それが 答えじゃないですか？
I suppose.
そうね
（車のクラクション）
Let's meet again soon.
（カリナ）また近いうちにね
Don't catch a cold.
（灼）風邪ひかないように
（カリナ）あ…
Thanks for your concern.
心配してくれて ありがと
Haruki Enomiya died in an accident.
榎宮春木(はるき)の事故死
三係が現場に到着すると―
By the time Unit Three arrived,
their underground casino was empty.
やつが経営していた裏カジノは
もぬけの殻で―
Enomiya's body was the only thing left.
榎宮の死体だけが
残されていたそうだ
（足音）
Inspectors.
監視官
What's wrong? You look serious.
（灼）どうしました？　怖い顔して
I have something for you.
あんたらに渡すもんがある
Enomiya's card
was among Yakushiji's effects.
榎宮の名刺は薬師寺の所持品だ
I got the other one when Irie,
the previous inspectors, and I
もう１つは
前の監視官と俺と入江が―
spoke to this man
during an investigation.
何かの捜査で この男に
話を聞いた時もらった
あ…
An investigation? Of what?
“何か”とは？
Neither inspector told us what it was
we were investigating.
２人の監視官のどっちも
何の捜査か俺たちには教えなかった
Then there was an accident.
で 事故が起こった
One inspector died
and the other was institutionalized.
監視官の１人が死に
１人が施設送りだ
Yes, I heard about that.
ええ そう聞いてます
The institutionalized one insists
（天馬）
事故じゃなく 殺しだと―
that it wasn't an accident. It was murder.
施設に入ったほうの監視官は
ずーっと言ってるらしい
Says a fox bit them.
“狐に かまれた”ってな
（灼）えっ？
No.
（灼）嫌だ… 嫌だよ 父さん
I don't want to, Dad.
You're closing the investigation
on the Enomiya case?
（霜月）
榎宮の件は捜査打ち切りですか
We won't find anything more.
（細呂木(ほそろぎ)）
これ以上は何も浮かぶまい
As with Unit One's former inspectors,
it both was, and was not, an accident.
（細呂木）
一係の前任監視官と同じく―
事故死であって事故死でない
"Bitten by a fox," was it?
“狐に かまれた”か
Is this a challenge to the system,
or an inadmissible bug in it?
これはシステムへの挑戦か
それとも あってはならないバグか
Either way, make good use of those two.
どちらにしても
あの２人をうまく使いたまえ
I know. I will flush out the foxes.
分かっています
必ず狐を狩り出します
At any cost.
どんな犠牲を出したとしても
♪～
Stupid perfection in your own castle
How smart. You cause me to yawn
Look,
The key to the door is in your hand
Don't you let anyone take control
What do you want?
Go get it. Play by your own rule
The winner always controls the game
You stand in your belief
There's no promising future
Always helpless
Crying for the moon
Finger trembles in fear
With the weight of the trigger
There's a way for us
Show them how we fight
Pull the trigger
～♪
"Psycho-Pass" refers to the measurement
of a person's mind and personality.
This is a work of fiction. Any resemblance
to real persons or groups is coincidental.